A story of natural love.
The Blue Lagoon is a adventure, drama, romance film directed by Randal Kleiser.
Two small children and a ship's cook survive a shipwreck and
find safety on an idyllic tropical island.
Soon, however, the cook dies and the young boy and girl are left on their own.
Days become years and Emmeline and Richard make a home for themselves
surrounded by exotic creatures and nature's beauty.
But will they ever see civilization again?
Emmeline, played by Brooke Shields.
Richard, played by Christopher Atkins.
Paddy Button, played by Leo McKern.
Arthur Lestrange, played by William Daniels.
Lookout, played by Jeffrey Kleiser.
Officer, played by Gus Mercurio.
The Blue Lagoon is a 1980 American drama film directed by Randal Kleiser from a screenplay written by
Douglas Day Stewart based on the 1908 novel of the same name by Henry De Vere Stacpoole.
The film stars Brooke Shields and Christopher Atkins.
The music score was composed by Basil Poledouris, and the
cinematography was by Néstor Almendros.
The film tells the story of a boy and a girl who live together in a tropical
island paradise in the South Pacific after surviving a shipwreck.
Without adult supervision or societal restrictions, the two navigate the emotional and physical changes of
puberty, fall in love, and have a child together before being rescued at the film's end.
The Blue Lagoon was theatrically released on June 20, 1980 by Columbia Pictures.
The film was panned by critics, who disparaged its screenplay, its execution, and
Shields' performance; however, Almendros' cinematography received praise.
In spite of the criticism, the film was a commercial success, grossing $58.8 million on a $4.5
million budget and becoming the ninth-highest-grossing film of 1980 in North America.
The film was nominated for the Saturn Award for Best Fantasy Film, the Academy Award for Best
Cinematography for Almendros, and the Golden Globe Award for New Star of the Year – Actor for Atkins.
Shields won the inaugural Golden Raspberry Award for
Worst Actress for her work in the film.
The film explores themes of sexual identity,
shipwreck, melancholy, lovers, stranded.
The tone is emotional.